

Ekta

Dodhia

Public Relations Manager and Blogger

https://ektadodhia74.wixsite.com/mine



ektadodhia74@gmail.com



+254737855848



1st parklands/ Nairobi/ Kenya



Indian Citizen

ABOUT ME

Innovative and experienced social media manager and blogger seeking to gain experience in public relations management with a Bachelor of Arts degree in Journalism. Knowledgeable in blog and article writing, copy editing, proposal writing, and Adobe software's. Equipped with quick problem-solving skills and delivers under pressure. Successfully designed the USIU-A 2019/2020 Yearbook.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism

United States International University - Africa (USIU-A) concentrating in Print media and PR & Advertising. 2017-01 to 2021-09

ACCA

Excel Global college 2016-09 to present

SKILLS

- Communication Skills
- Social Media Management
- Social Media Management tools
- Project Management
- Content Development, Editing and Social Media Scheduling
- SEO and Keyword Research
- Team Player
- Leadership skills

SOFTWARES

- InDesign
- Photoshop
- Canva
- Illustrator
- MS office

EXPERIENCE

Oshwal Education & Relief Board

PR Assistant 2022-08 to 2023-04

- Designed social media posts such as posters, infographics, carousels, and videos using content creation tools such as Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Designed the yearbook for 2 campuses using Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Captured Photos and videos of major events at the different campuses and edited them for use on the various social media platform.
- Suggested marketing strategies for implementation.

Outliers Marketing Ltd

2021-09 to 2022-08

- Designed social media posts such as posters, infographics, carousels, and videos using content creation tools such as Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Wrote, proofread, and edited Proposals to pitch to clients for marketing.

NanoVenue

Internship 2021-02 to 2021 -08

- Managed Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook using Creator Studio and TweetDeck social media management tools - Grew social media following 15%
- Designed social media posts such as posters, infographics, carousels, and videos using content creation tools such as Canva - Posted at least 3 times daily increasing page visits and engagement.
- Developed a social media calendar using Trello for project management Ensured social media content is available ahead of time.
- Wrote, proofread, and edited 11+ blog articles on company niche areas for publishing on the
 official website.
- Oversaw the development of 18 project proposals as the head of the proposal development department - Pitched 2 of these projects to different stakeholders.

Yearbook Committee

USIU-A yearbook 2019-11 to 2020-10

- Designed the layout and content for the book using software like Publisher, InDesign, and Photoshop in a team of 7 people.
- Used creative and critical thinking skills to solve design issues Delivered on a visually appealing book that was highly praised and widely read by the population of 5,000+ students.
- Took Photos of major events at the university and edited them for use within the yearbook for execution of that year's theme.

Electoral College

Part of the student's body for the year 2019/2020 at USIU-A

- Wrote 5+ proposals and tabled them for consideration as the representative of the school of communication – 2 were adopted and executed including the budget.
- Captured committee meeting minutes as the secretary for effective communication and follow-up of activities - promoted a cordial work environment for the committee.
- Used leadership, critical thinking, and creative problem-solving skills to deliver on the yearbook project on time.

CERTIFICATES AND

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2022-09 OPL Cricket Emcee
- 2022-08 Organized the Paryushan events as Visa Oshwal community religion secretary
- 2019-03 VCT Week Committee
- 2019-03 Won a Trophy for 1st Runners up as Team India in our inter-cultural competition.
- 2018-03 to 2019-03 Chair of Team India
- 2013-04 Certificate of Participation in the Music and Dance Night 2013
- 2015-11 Certificate for Coming 3rd Place in Pedal Kart
- 2009-11 Certificate of Participation in President's Awards Expedition Challenge.
- 2015-07 Certificate for Successfully Completing Tapovan NRI Shibhir
- 2015-02 Certificate of Participation in The Annual CAS Tournament 2015 and coming 3rd place.
- 2014-09 Certificate of Appreciation for Voluntary Service Provided during the Samvansari Lunch
- 2012-09 Certificate of Successful Completion of Work Placement at B.C. Patel & Co. and Mister Wok Restaurant
- 2012-06 Certificate of Assistance and Voluntary Services for Oshwal Census
- 2012-01 Certificate of Representation the Academy in Inter-School Under 13 Rounders Championships